{"data":{"site":{"pathPrefix":"/restaurant-inspections"},"postgres":{"establishment":[{"establishmentid":"457","name":"Roma Cafe Inc","address":"3401 Riopelle St","zipcode":"48207","owner":"Janet Sossi Belcoure","licenseNumber":"200065","licenseType":"Fixed Establishment","establishmentType":"Food Service Establishment","establishmentStatus":"Open","riskCategory":"High","reviewFrequencyDays":"180.0","coords":"-83.04179,42.35094","geojson":{"id":"457","type":"Feature","geometry":{"type":"Point","coordinates":[-83.041789465,42.350936275]},"properties":{"name":"Roma Cafe Inc","owner":"Janet Sossi Belcoure","address":"3401 Riopelle St","zipcode":"48207","license_type":"Fixed Establishment","risk_category":"High","license_number":"200065","establishmentid":"457","establishment_type":"Food Service Establishment","establishment_status":"Open","review_frequency_days":"180.0","most_recent_license_date":"4/24/2017"}},"nearbyList":[{"establishmentid":"51622579","name":"Amore Da Roma","address":"3401 Riopelle St","zipcode":"48207"},{"establishmentid":"51622477","name":"The Eastern","address":"3434 Russell St, Unit 501","zipcode":"48207"},{"establishmentid":"2714","name":"Sala Thai","address":"3400 Russell St","zipcode":"48207"},{"establishmentid":"5048","name":"Eastern Market Coproration Shed #5","address":"2934 Russell St","zipcode":"48207"},{"establishmentid":"3864","name":"Urban Grounds, LLC","address":"2934 Russell St","zipcode":"48207"},{"establishmentid":"2779","name":"Louie's Ham & Corned Beef","address":"3570 Riopelle St","zipcode":"48207"},{"establishmentid":"4634","name":"Bert's Market Place--Motown Bar","address":"2735 Russell St","zipcode":"48207"},{"establishmentid":"462","name":"Big Mike Coney Island Inc.","address":"2719 Russell St","zipcode":"48207"},{"establishmentid":"4656","name":"Detroit Edison Public School Academy","address":"3403 St Aubin","zipcode":"48207"},{"establishmentid":"3183","name":"Detroit Edison Public School Academy","address":"1903 Wilkins","zipcode":"48207"}],"inspectionsByEstablishmentidList":[{"inspectionid":"43128","inspectionDate":"2017-11-27T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Preopening/New","inCompliance":"No","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"5-402.11","violationDescription":"Except as otherwise allowed, a direct connection may not exist between the SEWAGE system and a drain originating from EQUIPMENT in which FOOD, portable EQUIPMENT, or UTENSILS are placed. (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Backflow/backsiphonage prevention device(s)","subItem":"Air gap","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"KETTLE ROOM","subLocation":"Three compartment sink","corrected":"No","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"4-402.11","violationDescription":"EQUIPMENT that is fixed because it is not EASILY MOVABLE shall be installed so that it is spaced to allow access for cleaning along the sides, behind, and above the EQUIPMENT or sealed as required,  COUNTER-MOUNTED EQUIPMENT that is not EASILY MOVABLE shall be installed to allow cleaning of the EQUIPMENT and areas underneath and around the EQUIPMENT .\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Fixed equipment","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not sealed to adjoining","subProblem":"Wall(s)","location":"WALK-IN COOLER & FREEZER","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Seal to wall/equipment to facilitate cleaning."},{"violationCode":"6-501.11","violationDescription":"PHYSICAL FACILITIES shall be maintained in good repair.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Physical facilities","subItem":"","problemDescription":"In poor repair","subProblem":"","location":"THROUGHOUT FACILITY","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null}]},{"inspectionid":"37904","inspectionDate":"2017-02-06T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"3-501.16","violationDescription":"Except during preparation, cooking, or cooling, or when time is used as the public health control POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be maintained:\r\n(A)  135ºF or above, except that roasts properly cooked and cooled may be held              at a temperature of 130ºF; or (P)\r\n(B)   At 41ºF or less (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Cold food item(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored above 41 degrees F","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"Cooler (salad)","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-02-06T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Discard"},{"violationCode":"2-301.14","violationDescription":"FOOD EMPLOYEES shall clean their hands and exposed portions of their arms as specified under § 2-301.12 immediately before engaging in FOOD preparation including working with exposed FOOD, clean EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS, and unwrapped SINGLE-SERVICE and SINGLE-USE ARTICLES (P) and:\r\n(A)     After touching bare human body parts other than clean hands and clean, exposed portions of arms; (P)\r\n(B)     After using the toilet room; (P)\r\n(C)     After caring for or handling SERVICE ANIMALS or aquatic animals as specified in ¶ 2-403.11(B); (P).\r\n(D)     Except as specified in ¶ 2-401.11(B), after coughing, sneezing, using a handkerchief or disposable tissue, using tobacco, eating, or drinking; (P)\r\n(E)     After handling soiled EQUIPMENT or UTENSILS; (P)\r\n(F)     During FOOD preparation, as often as necessary to remove soil and contamination and to prevent cross contamination when changing tasks; (P)\r\n(G)     When switching between working with raw FOOD and working with READY-TO-EAT FOOD; (P)\r\n(H)     Before donning gloves for working with FOOD; (P) and\r\n(I)      After engaging in other activities that contaminate the hands. (P)","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Employee(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Did not wash hands","subProblem":" after handling soiled equipment, surfaces, utensils","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"Lack of HAND WASHING","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-03-17T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Hands shall be washed with hot water and soap for at least 20 seconds after contamination."},{"violationCode":"4-501.112","violationDescription":"In a mechanical operation, the temperature of the fresh hot water SANITIZING rinse as it enters the manifold may not be more than 194 F, or less than 165 F for stationary rack machines or 180 F for all other machines to assure proper sanitizing of utensils. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Dish machine final rinse temperature","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Less than 180 degrees F","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"Dishwasher","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-03-17T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Repair to provide temperature stated above."},{"violationCode":"3-501.15","violationDescription":"(A) Cooling shall be accomplished in accordance with the time and temperature criteria specified under § 3-501.14 by using one or more of the following methods based on the type of FOOD being cooled:  \r\n   (1) Placing the FOOD in shallow pans; (Pf)\r\n   (2) Separating the FOOD into smaller or thinner portions; (Pf)\r\n   (3) Using rapid cooling EQUIPMENT; (Pf)\r\n   (4) Stirring the FOOD in a container placed in an ice water bath; (Pf)\r\n   (5) Using containers that facilitate heat transfer; (Pf)\r\n   (6) Adding ice as an ingredient; (Pf) or\r\n   (7) Other effective methods. (Pf)  \r\n(B) When placed in cooling or cold holding EQUIPMENT, FOOD containers in which FOOD is being cooled shall be:  \r\n   (1) Arranged in the EQUIPMENT to provide maximum heat transfer through the       container walls; and\r\n   (2) Loosely covered, or uncovered if protected from overhead contamination as          specified under Subparagraph 3-305.11(A)(2), during the cooling period to facilitate    heat transfer from the surface of the FOOD.","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Food item(s) cooled","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Improperly","subProblem":"Covered","location":"WALK-IN COOLER","subLocation":"IMPROPER COOLING","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-02-06T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Cool items uncovered on the top shelf of cooler."},{"violationCode":"3-501.17","violationDescription":"(A)  READY-TO-EAT, POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  prepared and held refrigerated for more than 24 hours in a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT  shall be clearly marked at the time of preparation to indicate the date or day by which the FOOD shall be consumed. (Pf)\r\n(B)  A container of refrigerated, commercially prepared READY-TO-EAT POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  shall be clearly marked, at the time the original container is opened in a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT, to indicate the date or day by which the FOOD shall be consumed. (Pf)\r\n\r\nA date marking system that does not exceed 7 days, including date of preparation, or opening is to be used. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"In house prepared ready-to-eat potentially hazardous  food(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Without date of consumption marking","subProblem":"","location":"COOLERS THROUGHOUT","subLocation":"Lack of DATE MARKING","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-03-17T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Datemark with a discard date of 7 days or less."},{"violationCode":"4-501.110","violationDescription":"(A) The temperature of the wash solution in spray type warewashers that use hot water to SANITIZERS may not be less than:     \r\n(1) For a stationary rack, single temperature machine, 74°C (165°F);(Pf)   \r\n(2) For a stationary rack, dual temperature machine, 66°C (150°F); (Pf)   \r\n(3) For a single tank, conveyor, dual temperature machine, 71°C (160°F);(Pf) or\r\n(4) For a multitank, conveyor, multitemperature machine, 66°C (150°F).(Pf)  \r\n(B) The temperature of the wash solution in spray-type warewashers that use chemicals to SANITIZE may not be less than 49°C (120°F). (Pf)","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Dish machine wash solution temperature","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Less than 150 degrees F","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"Dishwasher","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-03-17T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Repair to provide temperature stated above."},{"violationCode":"4-601.11","violationDescription":"(A) EQUIPMENT FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be clean to sight and touch. (Pf)\r\n(B) The FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of cooking EQUIPMENT and pans shall be kept free of encrusted grease deposits and other soil accumulations. \r\n(C) NonFOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of EQUIPMENT shall be kept free of an accumulation of dust, dirt, FOOD residue, and other debris. \r\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Food-contact surface(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"STORAGE ROOM","subLocation":"Food contact surfaces","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-03-17T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Clean."},{"violationCode":"MFL289.2129","violationDescription":"Sec. 2129. (1) All food establishments shall employ a minimum of 1 managerial employee as a food safety manager, who must be an individual who is currently certified under a personnel certification program accredited by the American National Standards Institute, utilizing the Conference for Food Protection standards:\r\n(2) Beginning January 14, 2017 and every 5 years thereafter, a certified  food safety manager who supervises the operations of a food service establishment shall have completed a food safety training program\r\ncontaining an allergen awareness  component that has been approved by  the department. A food service establishment shall retain records on the  site of the food service establishment documenting compliance of its  certified food safety managers with this subsection. ","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Person-in-charge","subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"PERSON IN CHARGE","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2017-03-17T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide."},{"violationCode":"3-302.11","violationDescription":"(A) FOOD shall be protected from cross contamination by:  \r\n(1) Except as specified in (1)(c) below, separating raw animal FOODS during         storage, preparation, holding, and display from:\r\n(a) Raw READY-TO-EAT FOOD including other raw animal FOOD such as FISH for sushi or MOLLUSCAN SHELLFISH, or other raw READY-TO-EAT FOOD such as fruits and vegetables,(P) and\r\n(b) Cooked READY-TO-EAT FOOD; (P)\r\n(c) Frozen, commercially processed and packaged raw animal FOOD may be          stored or displayed with or above frozen, commercially processed and           packaged, ready-to-eat food.\r\n(2) Except when combined as ingredients, separating types of raw animal FOODS    from each other such as beef, FISH, lamb, pork, and POULTRY during storage,        preparation, holding, and display by:\r\n(a) Using separate EQUIPMENT for each type, (P) or\r\n(b) Arranging each type of FOOD in EQUIPMENT so that cross contamination of one type with another is prevented, (P) and\r\n(c) Preparing each type of FOOD at different times or in separate areas; (P)\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Food","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not covered","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"In the Cooler (reach-in)","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-03-17T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Keep covered."},{"violationCode":"4-501.11","violationDescription":"EQUIPMENT shall be maintained in a state of repair and condition that meets the requirements of the code.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Equipment","subItem":"","problemDescription":"In poor repair","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"Cooler (salad)","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2017-03-17T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"6-501.18","violationDescription":"PLUMBING FIXTURES such as HANDWASHING SINKS, toilets, and urinals shall be cleaned as often as necessary to keep them clean. \r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Handwashing facility","subItem":"handwash","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"Handsink","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2017-03-17T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Clean."}]}]}],"maxInspectionDate":[{"inspectionDate":"2019-05-31T00:00:00"}]}},"pageContext":{"eid":"457"}}